Excel and other spreadsheet applications can do
Excel 和其他电子表格应用可以
a nice job of creating attractive tables and charts.
很好地创建吸引人的表格和图表
It's up to us to make them look their absolute best though.
但是需要我们自己手动设置 使它们看起来很美观
They should be readable,
它们应该易读
interesting and show the required information,
有趣并显示所需信息
but not show extra information that doesn't matter.
但是不显示不必要的多余信息
When you present data,
在展示数据时
think about what questions you're trying to
思考下试图回答的问题
answer and the patterns you're trying to show,
以及想要展现的规律
then use fonts and layouts appropriately to include and
然后适当地使用字体和布局
emphasize the elements that matter and exclude elements that don't.
来包含和强调重要的元素 并排除不重要的元素
Also, ask yourself who is your audience.
并且问问自己 受众是谁
Is this a quick overview presentation on a slide with the data backup elsewhere
只需要备份好数据 在幻灯片上的展示快速概要？
or is it a written technical review where more in-depth data should be presented?
还是需要书面技术概述 并且应该展示更深入的数据？
Let's look at some of the charts we created earlier and see if we can improve upon them.
回到我们之前创建的图表 看看能否完善它们
For categorical column data,
对于分类列数据
like the counts of the baseball positions,
例如棒球位置人数数据
the relative sizes are easier to see at a glance if the data is sorted by size.
如果数据按大小排序 那么更容易一眼就看出相对大小
This would not be something we would want to do for
对于每日股价或直方图组距等定序数据
sequential data like daily stock values or histogram bins,
则不能这么做
but it is more readable in this case.
但是这里更容易读懂
There should be a descriptive title,
应该设定描述性标题
so I'll put one in that says baseball positions.
我将标题设为 Baseball Positions
It should also be big enough to read.
并且应该字体足够大 能够看清
If you need to change the font or font size,
如果要更改字体或字号
this can be done by selecting the title and changing it in the Home tab.
可以选中标题并在开始菜单中进行更改
There, does this chart need a legend?
好了 该图表需要图例吗？
If there are more than one data series, it does,
如果有多个数据系列 则需要
but if the labels are already showing up in the data as in this pie chart,
但是如果标签已经显示在数据中 就像这个饼图一样
then an extra legend is just noise, so remove it.
则图例是多余信息 因此删了
For a graph, do you need or want grid lines?
对于某个图表 需要网格线吗？
In a detailed technical presentation,
在详细的技术演示文稿中
it is easier to see the values if there are grid lines,
如果有网格线 则更容易看清值
but for quick overviews that are just emphasizing the trend,
但是如果只是快速查看趋势
those extra lines look busy.
这些网格线就多余了
What about the axis labels?
坐标轴标签呢？
I hate it when I look at a graph and can't tell what the numbers on the axis represent,
我讨厌的是 不知道图表坐标轴上的数字代表什么
so I would generally say put them there,
因此通常可以添加到标题处
but there are always exceptions.
当然始终都有例外情况
If the units are redundant,
如果单位多余了
somehow, they can be removed.
可以删掉
The font size is a judgement call,
字号属于主观判断
but bigger is easier to read and draws attention.
字号越大 更容易看清并且能吸引注意力
So take a look at your chart and see if it can be improved.
看看你的图表是否有改进的地方
Color is a similar issue.
颜色也类似
It just depends.
取决于具体情况
Keep in mind that your chart may be printed in
注意 你的图表可能会打印为黑白图片
grayscale or viewed by someone who's colorblind.
或者受众是色盲人士
So if it's possible to distinguish groupings in
因此如果能用其他方式区分类别
additional ways such as different shapes and scatter plots,
例如不同的形状或散点图
or using dashes in lines,
或使用虚实线
it's a best practice to do so.
则最好这么做
The format data series dialogue has
格式数据系列对话框
a number of options for changing the look of your graph.
提供了更改图表外观的多种选项
This was just a sampling of some of the modifications you can make to
我只是介绍了几种修改方式
your charts to give them the impact you want in a professional presentation.
使你的图表看起来更专业
The best way to learn is to just try things, to explore.
最好的学习方法是尝试各种功能 积极探索